Santiago Bustamante Garcia

+57 300 330 1001 busta117@gmail.com skype: sbusta117 www.santiagobustamante.info

SUMMARY

I'm an engineer with several years of experience developing native iOS applications and games. I like working on an startup-style environment with a dynamic team all around the world. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both by myself and in a team.

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer, MedAnswers

Los Angeles, California, USA — oct 2018 - current

I'm a member and leader of the iOS developer team, working on support and implementation of new features for the App. https://apps.apple.com/app/fertilitvanswers/id1418650176

iOS Developer, TPaga

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — oct 2018 - jan 2019

I was a member of the iOS developer team, working on a support and implementation of new features for the wallet App. https://apps.apple.com/app/billetera-tpaga/id1163936960

iOS Developer, Barista Ventures

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — abr 2015 - oct 2018

I was a member and leader of the iOS developer team, these are some of the iOS apps I were working on: Sniffle Physician and Patient app (https://www.sniffle.com/), MedAnswers doctor and patient app (https://www.sniffle.com/), MedAnswers doctor and patient app (https://greenarmy.com), GreenArmy seller app (https://greenarmy.com), PickUp customer and driver iOS app (https://pickupnow.com), Brokenbox (doesn't exist anymore), working most of the time for startups in the US.

iOS Developer, Periferia IT

Bogotá, Cundinamarca, Colombia — apr 2014 - jun 2015

I was a member and leader of the iOS developer team, i was in charge of 3 iOS apps: The Squawka Football App (http://www.squawka.com), another app for a startup in UK named weHive(not in the store) and some apps for internal use of the company.

iOS Developer, Rokk3r Labs

Bogotá, Cundinamarca, Colombia — oct 2014 - may 2015

I was an outsourced iOS developer, i worked in 4 iOS apps for startups in the USA including HotSwitch (https://www.hotswitch.com), other startups don't exist anymore.

iOS Developer, KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — jun 2013 - apr 2014

I was a member of the iOS development team, I was in charge of several apps and participated in the development of more than 6 other apps, signed an NDA.

iOS Developer, GARA Entertainment

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — dec 2011 - jun 2013

I developed several games using Objective-C and frameworks such as cocos2D, box2D and Unity. I developed native iOS apps and theirs backend in php and WCF. I was in charge of the development of Oh My Nuts! Game (https://youtu.be/RfIVtL0y690), their free version and two other games that are not in the AppStore, GoBo(http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ_NE) and StreetRep (http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM); also i developed the ipad version of an app for a Colombian retail firm named ÉXITO

iOS Developer, Doctus LTDA

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia — jun 2011 - dec 2011

I developed several frameworks for use in house and also started the development of some iOS games.

iOS Developer, Freelance

I developed several iOS native apps for independent clients, some of these applications are still live in the AppStore and some other was just for an specific event or for an advertising strategy:

- DIAN (https://apps.apple.com/app/id1494932986)
- App for a Marathon in Medellin-Colombia for 2 years (http://maratonmedellin.com)
- Medellin Hip Hop (internet radio station, app is not in the store anymore)
- Sushi Market (sushi restaurant in Medellin-Colombia, app is not in the store anymore)
- events list for ANDI (app is not available in the AppStore)
- social network using GPS called MNU (app is not available in the AppStore)

TUAPP Contest 2013

I participated in the University Apps Contest powered by Cursor in Santiago de Chile, we were finalists with an application that suggests other ways of tourism using quests (http://www.tuapp.org/).

EDUCATION

EAFIT University (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

SKILLS

- Swift
- Objective-C
- Reactive programming on iOS
- Realm
- Xcode
- Memory management and debugging for iOS apps using instruments.
- Sketch
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, premiere)